Bruce Trupo

Electrical Lead/Commercial Project Manager - Paul Zensky Electrical Contractors/ Vanguard Energy Partners LLC

Magnolia, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Bruce-Trupo/905e94279282f356

I am seeking a career in a Management role utilizing 17 years of leadership responsibilities, training, coordination, administrative, and logistical management. I also am able to utilize my communication skills with your everyday person, which enables me to relate, and understand the many types of personalities and everyday demands of the community, an employee, customer and employer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Electrical Lead/Commercial Project Manager

Paul Zensky Electrical Contractors/ Vanguard Energy Partners LLC - 2008 to Present

While with Paul Zensky Electrical Contractors/ Vanguard Energy Partners LLC, I have installed various types of Solar systems from 5.5 kW to 3.86 MW. I have working knowledge of various types of inverters from: Froniuos, Xantrex, Satcon and Sunny Boy. Projects that I have been part of include ground arrays, carports or rooftops for the commercial clients. I have provided a list of some jobs that have been done to date. Some other job duties include residential and commercial application.

Some of the projects I have worked on:

- -Hall's Refrigeration Warehouse, South Plainfield, NJ (3.86 Mw)
- -Fort Lee MUA, Community Center, and Police Department, Fort Lee, NJ (200 Kw)
- -Morristown Waste Water Treatment Facility, Morristown, NJ (750 Kw)
- -Mcguire Air Force Base Medical Facility/Library, Wrightstown, NJ (110 Kw)
- -Black River Farm, Ringoes, NJ (87 Kw)
- -Charles Elementary School, Palmyra, NJ (75 Kw)
- -Fairton Federal Prison, Fairton, NJ (400 Kw)
- -Fimble Door, Branchburg, NJ (375 Kw)
- -Paige Wire, Springfield, NJ (500 Kw)
- -DCC, Union, NJ (250 Kw)
- -Deutsche Bank, Piscataway, NJ (1.2Mw)
- -Pem America, Cranbury, NJ (711 Kw)
- -Alliance Shippers, Metuchen, NJ (800 Kw)
- -Somerset School District, Phase II, (2.5 Mw)

I have worked on multiple jobs with a crew of 3 to 45 personnel under my direction, I have also had to keep a complete log of job duties performed by all individual crewman and daily progression sheets to ensure timely job completion.

I have installed various other residential systems to include rooftop, ground mount and trakker systems, in excess of 4 Mw+. I have also been tasked with installation and trouble shooting of all communications for all inverters, to include parameter settings and reading data logs for all inverter types.

I have a running total of over 35 Mw of solar as a Project Manager, both working and non-working.

Electrician/Foreman

Pitt Bull Electric, Inc - 2002 to 2008

While with Pitt Bull Electric, Inc., as an electrical Foreman, for the Photovoltaic side the company, I have a working knowledge in commercial applications. I have worked with both AC and DC applications. Some experience I posses are print reading, pipe bending, circuitry, and layout. I have held the position of lead and assistant foreman and have been tasked with the maintaining of continuous flow on projects with coordination and material supplies for job completion.

Some of the following projects that I have worked on in the past:

- -Hilton Hotel, Valley Forge
- -Hilltop Elementary School, Chichester, Pa.
- -Cumberland County Prison
- -Rieck Avenue Elementary School, Millville, NJ
- -RL Carrier, Burlington, NJ
- -Sugartown Elementary, Malvern, Pa
- -Hilltop Elementary, Chichester, Pa.
- -ARMM & Associates-Photovoltaic (40-60 Kw)
- -Pathmark Photovoltaic (225-250 Kw) Lawnside 250Kw, Elizabeth 225Kw, and Garwood 250Kw, NJ

Civil Engineer

U.S. Air Force Reserve - 1998 to 2007

For nine years have trained and been educated in all aspects of structural framing, drywall, duct fabrication and installation, masonry, welding, and concrete all being sponsored by the University of the Air Force Civil Engineering Program. I have been Honorable discharged from the 514 CES Squadron, from McGuire AFB, NJ, where I perform the various duties of carpentry, while working hand in hand with numerous other trades and even cross training if the training requires me to do so.

Trained and received 696 hours of apprenticeship classroom time while in Gulf Port, Mississippi and over well beyond 10000 hours of practical application in the construction of buildings from foundation on up. I also am qualified in MIG and TIG welding.

Some of my extra duty features include: Sweep and Clear NCOIC; I am in charge of training and coordination of a squad level group in proper patrolling and clearing of hostile areas.

Project Manager

Tradesource, inc - Cherry Hill, NJ - 2001 to 2003

Held a position as the Project Manager; my job duties consist of sales and recruiting for the local NJ, Delaware, and Southeastern Pennsylvania areas. My normal daily functions are to produce an abundance of work orders and maintain a high demand of quality workers to meet the needs of over 300 contractors per trade. The various trades include: Carpentry, Electrical, HVAC, Plumbing, Masonry, and everyday General Labor.

Job Duties include the maintaining of administrative and logistical needs of tradesman working for me, to include; payroll, hiring/termination of tradesman, medical and workers comp benefits, and their everyday personal needs. While with Trade Source, I was able to average my sales on a run rate of over 2.5 million dollars for the year; this was after being forecasted at 1.185 million and doing so as a single man office.

carpenter

C&C Construction - Red Bank, NJ - 1998 to 2001

area

-Cranberry Assisted Living, in Cherry Hill NJ

-Abington Police Training Facility, in Abington, Pa.

Infantryman

U.S. Marine Corp - 1994 to 1998

Trained in many aspects of leadership, management and organization of troops from personal welfare and work relationship. Have the working ability to direct or lead anywhere from 6 to 175 personnel at one time. Counseling skills in job performance and discipline of personnel.

I have held such positions as squad leader as an E-2, Section Leader and acting Platoon Sergeant as an E-3, FDC Chief while with an 81mm Mortar Platoon. Some specialty training included weapons training with anything from a pistol to high impact weapons.

My Training has also included various close quarter training, ammunition and explosives handling, and I have also been trained in the use of many different weapons from small arms to large scale weapons.

EDUCATION

BS in Human Resource Development

Camden County Institute of Technology in Pennsauken - Pennsauken, NJ 2001 to 2007

Civil Engineering Squadron

Air Force University 1998 to 2001

Marine Corp. Institute of Technology and NCO Academy. 1994 to 1998

High School Diploma

Deptford High School 1990 to 1994

MILITARY SERVICE

Service Country: US Branch: USMC Rank: Sgt/E-5

June 1994 to June 1998

Served honorably while in the Marine Corp. Held many different billets from squad leader to platoon Sgt.

Commendations:

-NAVY ACHIEVEMENT MEDAL-GOOD CONDUCT MEDAL-(2) CERTIFICATES OF COMMENDATION FOR EXCELLENCE IN PERFORMANCE.

CERTIFICATIONS

OSHA 10

October 2011 to Present

Aerial Work Platforms

June 2012 to June 2015

FORKLIFT operator training

June 2012 to June 2015

Certificates of completion for Apprenticeship I, II, III, and IV

September 2002 to May 2007

Certificates for passing each year of my required apprenticeship education per year.